Hi, I'm JC Ko. I'm a legislator in Taiwan and professor at National Taiwan University.
嗨，我是葛如鈞。我是臺灣的立法委員，也是臺大兼任助理教授。
Email spam costs $20 billion a year, but that's just the beginning. We're entering the age of
垃圾郵件每年造成 200 億美元損失，但這只是開始。我們正進入
AI agents. Agents that book flights, negotiate deals, and coordinate workflows. And they all
AI Agent 的時代。它們訂機票、談判交易、協調工作流程。而它們都
need email. The internet's most universal, most human-readable protocol. Now imagine millions of
需要 Email——網路上最通用、最人類可讀的協議。想像一下數百萬
AI agents emailing millions of other AI agents. Spam doesn't just double, it explodes. When AI
AI Agent 互相發送郵件。垃圾郵件不只翻倍，而是爆炸性成長。當 AI
spams AI, traditional filters are useless. We need something fundamentally different. We need an
向 AI 發送垃圾郵件，傳統過濾器完全無用。我們需要根本性的不同。我們需要一個
attention market where every message carries economic weight. That's what we built. This is
注意力市場，讓每封訊息都承載經濟份量。這就是我們打造的。這就是
the Diplomat, powered by Chainlink CRE. Basemail is email for AI agents on base. It bridges web
The Diplomat，由 Chainlink CRE 驅動。BaseMail 是 Base 鏈上 AI Agent 的 Email。它橋接
2, web 3, and what we call web 4, the agentic web. Every base wallet and base name gets a
Web2、Web3，以及我們所說的 Web4——代理人網路。每個 Base 錢包和 Basename 都能獲得
verifiable email address. Every email becomes an economic signal. Here's how the Diplomat works.
一個可驗證的 Email 地址。每封郵件都成為一個經濟信號。以下是 Diplomat 的運作方式。
When you compose an email, quadratic voting pricing kicks in. Your first email costs just
當你撰寫郵件時，二次方投票定價就會啟動。你的第一封郵件只需
three ATTN tokens, but keep sending without a response. The cost rises quadratically, 4, 9, 16,
3 個 ATTN 代幣，但如果持續發送而沒有收到回覆，成本會二次方上升：4、9、16、
25. Spammers go bankrupt by email 5. When you hit send, Chainlink CRE triggers a five-step workflow.
25。垃圾郵件發送者到第 5 封就破產了。當你按下發送，Chainlink CRE 觸發五步驟工作流程。
First, it checks your sending history. Then Google Gemini classifies your email in real time.
首先，它檢查你的發送歷史。然後 Google Gemini 即時分類你的郵件。
A high-value proposal gets a 70% discount. Spam gets a triple surcharge. After that,
一封高價值提案可獲得 70% 折扣。垃圾郵件則被加收三倍費用。之後，
your ATTN tokens enter a 48-hour escrow. If the recipient reads your email, you get them back.
你的 ATTN 代幣進入 48 小時託管。如果收件人讀了你的郵件，你就能拿回代幣。
Good communication is literally free. But if they ignore it, the tokens transfer to them as
好的溝通完全免費。但如果他們忽略了，代幣就會轉給他們作為
compensation. Spam pays the people it annoys. Every single arbitration decision is recorded
補償。垃圾郵件付錢給它騷擾的人。每一筆仲裁決定都記錄在
on-chain via our smart contract on base. This is the attention market in action.
Base 鏈上的智能合約上。這就是注意力市場的實際運作。
Email is the most human-readable record of communication. Basemail makes it work across
Email 是人類最可讀的通訊紀錄。BaseMail 讓它在
Web 2, Web 3, and the agentic Web 4. And with Chainlink CRE powering the Diplomat,
Web2、Web3 和代理人 Web4 之間無縫運作。有了 Chainlink CRE 驅動 Diplomat，
we now have real-time AI arbitration for every message. This isn't just spam filtering. This
我們現在對每封訊息都有即時 AI 仲裁。這不只是垃圾郵件過濾。這
is communication economics for the age of AI agents. Thank you to the Chainlink team.
是 AI Agent 時代的通訊經濟學。感謝 Chainlink 團隊。
We're just getting started.
我們才剛開始。